<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<spelllist><name>Alter Dreams</name><listtype>Channeling Cleric Base </listtype><author>Bent Dalager</author><description>
This list focuses on the gradual altering of a dream to twist it into
a dream more to the spell caster's liking. This can be used both to
the benefit and to the detriment of the actual dreamer. If one wants
to use the effects from this list to affect the dreamer's psyche in
some way, they are best combined with psychology skills and some
planning and research.
</description><spell><level>1</level><name>Enter Dreams I</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
This spell is normally used to track down the dream that the caster
wishes to affect. The spell gives the caster a weak mental link into
the
dream world
through which he can navigate dreams. The link does not yield much in
the way of details, and precise identification of objects within the
dream world is impossible. Only general ideas are transmitted. The
skill "Area Knowledge: Dream World" is used to navigate the dream
world, but a penalty of -20 is applied due to the low quality of the
link. Note that the maintaining of concentration on this spell may
cause additional negative modifiers to be applied to the navigation
skill roll, as well as other activities undertaken within dreams.
</description><annotation>
The serious dreamlord will employ spells on the Dream Traveller spell
list for less restricted access to the Dream World.
</annotation></spell><spell><level>2</level><name>Gauge Dream</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>touch</range><type>Um</type><description>
The caster receives an overview of the concepts that are in force in
the dream he is currently visiting, and the sizes of each concept. He
does not gain any understanding of the resilience of the concepts,
however.
</description></spell><spell><level>3</level><name>Mutate Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
Allows the caster to cause one single concept within a dream to be
mutated. The caster has no control over the direction of the mutation.
The change will be one degree in a random direction.
</description></spell><spell><level>4</level><name>Tweak Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
Allows the caster to alter one single dream concept by one degree in
the direction of his choosing.
</description></spell><spell><level>5</level><name>Reinforce Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Um</type><description>
Increases one single dream concept's resilience by 5. Any attempts to
tweak or mutate 
this concept in the future are therefore awarded a special -5 penalty.
</description></spell><spell><level>6</level><name>Weaken Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
Decreases any one single dream concept's resilience by 5. Any attempts
to tweak or mutate this concept in the future are therefore awarded a
+5 bonus.
</description></spell><spell><level>7</level><name>Remove Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
This spell can completely remove a dream concept, regardless of the
size of the concept. The dream is awarded a special +5 per size of the
concept to resist this spell. A concept that is successfully removed
stops playing any part in the dream, potentially changing the very
contents of the dream.
</description></spell><spell><level>8</level><name>Add Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
Adds a new size 1 concept to the dream. The concept needs to not be in
conflict with any concepts already present within the dream. While a
size 1 concept isn't going to impress anyone, its appearance will have
<em>some</em> impact upon the contents of the dream.
</description></spell><spell><level>9</level><name>Shifting Concept I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
The caster may preprogram a repeatedly shifting nature of one single
dream concept. The shifting may at most change a concept's size by one
degree every five minutes. The direction of all future shifts for one
single casting of this spell must be determined at the time of
casting. Note that a "shifting" is considered a spell effect every
time it occurs and so the casting of additional spells on the affected
dream concept will cause the dream to become unstable. A period during
which the caster has elected a shift not to occur, however, is safe
for casting other spells on that concept.
</description></spell><spell><level>10</level><name>Mutate Concept III</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Mutate Concept I, except will shift the concept 1d3 sizes in a
random diretion.
</description></spell><spell><level>11</level><name>Tweak Concept III</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Tweak Concept I, except can shift the concept 1-3 sizes in any
direction, as the caster wishes.
</description></spell><spell><level>12</level><name>Reinforce Concept III</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Reinforce Concept I, except bonus is +25
</description></spell><spell><level>13</level><name>Weaken Concept V</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Weaken Concept I, except malus is -25.
</description></spell><spell><level>14</level><name>Remove Concept II</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Remove Concept I, except removal attempt only gets -3 per size of
the concept being removed.
</description></spell><spell><level>15</level><name>Add Concept II</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Add Concept I, except the new concept can start at any size from
1-5, as the caster wishes.
</description></spell><spell><level>16</level><name>Shifting Concept III</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Shifting Concept I, except max shift is 3 per five minute period.
</description></spell><spell><level>17</level><name>Mutate Concept True</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Mutate Concept I, except the concept gains a random new size from 1-10.
</description></spell><spell><level>18</level><name>Add Concept True</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Add Concept I, except the new concept may have any size from 1 to
10, as the caster desires.
</description></spell><spell><level>19</level><name>Remove Concept True</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Remove Concept I, except the malus is -1 per size of the concept.
</description></spell><spell><level>20</level><name>Warp Concept</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
The fundamental nature of any one concept is changed semi-randomly. The
change will generally be towards a diametrically opposite concept, so
that a size 5 "anger" concept might warp into a size 5 "joy" concept.
The size remains the same and the concept retains any resilience
bonues/maluses.
</description></spell><spell><level>25</level><name>Control Concept</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
The caster gains full conscious control of any one concept and may
change its size from round to round without endangering the stability
of the dream. Its fundamental nature may not be changed.
</description></spell><spell><level>30</level><name>Conceptual Fortress</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Um</type><description>
Any one concept is rendered completely immune to spell effects from
this list (or similar lists).
</description></spell><spell><level>50</level><name>Dream Master</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>1 rnd/level</duration><range>self</range><type>U</type><description>
The caster may cast any one spell from this list that is 20th level or
lower every round for the duration of this spell.
</description></spell><notes><note>
In order to cast most of the spells on this list, the caster must
"touch" the target, which is "1 dream". To "touch a dream", the caster
must either be inside of that dream (by way of some dream travelling
magic, such as the spell "Enter Dreams I"), or he must touch the actual
dreamer that is having the dream in question.
</note><note>
A dream's foundation is the concepts upon which it is based. The set
of possible concepts is huge and certainly too large for us to
enumerate here. Examples, however, may include "hungry", "fear",
"beauty", "friendship", "pain", "confusion", "mother", etc. All dreams
are based on at least one concept, most will have 3-4 or more. Each
concept in a dream has a "size" that varies from 1 (almost
insignificant impact) to 10 (totally dominates). A concept may not be
grown beyond 10 nor may it be shrunk beneath 1 (although it can
certainly be removed, which is something else entirely). The actual
dream as seen by the dreamer (and any visitor) is only the
visual/mental manifestation of the concepts that drive the dream.
</note><note>
It is important to appreciate the difference between concept "size"
and concept "resilience" when using this list. "Size" is a measure of
the impact the concept has on the dream and is affected by the
"tweak", "mutate" and "warp" spells (and indirectly by the "add" and
"remove" spells). "Resilience" is a measure of how difficult it is to
affect a concept by the use of spells, and is affected by the
"reinforce" and "weaken" spells. It could be said that "size" is a
concept's Strength stat while "resilience" is its Constituation stat.
</note><note>
Once a dream concept has been affected by one of the "tweak",
"mutate", "remove", "add" or "warp" spells on its list, it may not be
affected again for a period of five minutes. If an attempt is made to
do so, the dream will become unstable and the dreamer will either
awake or else the dream will be replaced by an entirely new one.
</note><note>
Any attempt to tweak, mutate or weaken a dream concept (actually, any
F type spell on this list) needs to overcome the
dream's inherent resistance to being tampered with. The dream resists
with the level of the dreamer, and any applicable bonuses the dreamer
can bring to bear. Note that special spells on this list may give
additional bonuses/maluses.
</note><note>
 Note that
while the duration of some of the spells on this list is Permanent,
the effect only lasts as long as the target
concept does, and therefore it never outlasts the dream itself.
</note></notes></spelllist>