<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<spelllist><name>Dream Walls</name><listtype>Channeling Cleric Base </listtype><author>Bent Dalager</author><description>
This spell list is primarly used for protecting someone's dreams from
intrusion, and for getting rid of unwanted interference. It can also,
however, be put to good use invading the minds of others and should be
considered a definite maybe for any would-be usurper of dreams.
</description><spell><level>1</level><name>Dream Sentry I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>10'</range><type>F</type><description>
This spell creates a special type of dream fragment - a dream creature
with a purpose outside of that of the dream itself. This creature will
seek out and attack visitors within the dream. It is considered to
have a skill bonus equal to five times its level when it comes to
detecting visitors. The caster may designate one specific visitor per
level of the creature that will be spared the creature's wrath. The
creature will attempt not to interfere with the dream itself, but will
do so if it proves necessary in order to get rid an unwanted visitor.
The creature will exist until it is destroyed or the dream it was
created in ends. The sentry created with this spell cannot be higher
than first level (a class I entity). It will have physical and combat
stats comparable to a created undead of its own level.
</description></spell><spell><level>2</level><name>Detect Visitor</name><areaofeffect>5'R</areaofeffect><duration>1 min/lvl(C)</duration><range>100'</range><type>P</type><description>
Cast from within a dream, detects the presence of any visitor. Caster
can concentrate on a 5'R area of the dream every round.
</description></spell><spell><level>3</level><name>Dream Sentry II</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>10'</range><type>F</type><description>
As Dream Sentry I, except max creature level is 3 (a class II entity).
</description></spell><spell><level>4</level><name>Monitor Dream</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>touch</range><type>P</type><description>
Caster goes into a trance where he can monitor the entry or exit of
visitors in a dream. If any visitor enters or exits the dream, the
caster will know that this has happened. No details are learned, only
the number of visitors and whether they entered or left. The caster
does specifically not learn who it was or where they are/were.
</description></spell><spell><level>5</level><name>Expell Visitor I</name><areaofeffect>1 visitor</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>50'</range><type>Fm</type><description>
If target visitor does not resist, he is immediately expelled from the
dream. He will typically end up in another dream that is similar.
</description></spell><spell><level>6</level><name>Waiting Wall</name><areaofeffect>1 spell</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>-</range><type>U</type><description>
When cast prior to the casting of any other spell (which
must be cast within one minute of casting "Waiting Wall"), the actual
effect of the second spell is delayed. 
Alternatively, this spell can be cast without an
accompanying spell, in which case it will simply alert the caster that
the trigger action occurs. The duration is until the spell is
triggered, or until the dream it is cast in ends.
The spell may trigger on any
one of the following conditions; time, a specific observable
occurrence or
information that could be gleaned through the use of "Detect Visitor"
or "Monitor Dream". Note that if a "Detect Visitor" trigger is
chosen, a specific non-moving 5'R must be chosen and this area will be
constantly monitored. The caster need not cast or pay power points for
the detection spells if such a trigger is chosen - it is built into
this spell.
</description><annotation>
While it may be tempting to use this spell to delay an "Expell
Visitor" spell on a "Monitor Dream" type of trigger, that will not
work.
"Monitor Dream" does not supply the information needed to accurately
target the visitor and so the "Expell Visitor" spell will fizzle. One
could in stead use a "Detect Visitor" trigger, but this does of course
quite drastically limit the area that can be monitored.
</annotation><annotation>
It is possibly to nest "Waiting Wall" spells for sophisticated effects.
That is, one could cast a "Waiting Wall" spell that triggers on a
"Monitor Dream" trigger of "a visitor has entered the dream". The
spell triggered could be another "Waiting Wall" spell set up to
trigger on "Detect Visitor" and launch an "Expell Visitor" spell
when a visitor is detected. While it is not clear why this
particular case would be useful, it does illustrate the concept.
</annotation><annotation>
A common spell mastering of this spell might be to introduce other
means of triggering. For instance, one might want the spell to trigger
when the sun in the real world comes out from behind the clouds. This
information is not readily available within the dream world and so the
caster would have to join this spell with either another spell or else
some unconventional forms of perception to detect that occurrence. In
these cases, this spell should be considered to have been originally
designed with these cases in mind, and so introducing new forms of
triggers into it shouldn't be excessively difficult. In the cases when
these triggers rely upon another spell known by the caster, he may
need to cast that spell in addition to this one. This costs extra
power points and it might make him a bit pressed for time as he only
has one minute from the casting of this spell until he must cast the
waiting spell. This puts a natural limit on how many fancy effects he
can introduce.
</annotation></spell><spell><level>7</level><name>Terminate Dream</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
The dreamer gets to resist this spell. If the spell is successful, the
targetted dream ends. The dreamer will most often enter a new dream,
but may awaken at the GM's discretion. Any visitors within the old
dream will be expelled as it ends and will have to track down the new
dream if they want back to the same dreamer.
</description></spell><spell><level>8</level><name>Dream Sentry III</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>10'</range><type>F</type><description>
As Dream Sentry I, except max creature level is 6 (a class III entity).
</description></spell><spell><level>9</level><name>True Insomnia</name><areaofeffect>1 target</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
While under the effect of this spell, the target is completely
incapable of falling asleep. After suffering the effect of this spell
for two days, the target is at -25 to all actions. If the effect
continues for a prolonged period of time, the target risks losing his
mind. This spell will detect as a curse and is dispellable as such.
</description><annotation>
Some times the cure is as bad as the disease, but if you have demons
infesting your dreams, "True Insomnia" may be just what the doctor
ordered.
</annotation></spell><spell><level>10</level><name>Dream Barrier I</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>touch</range><type>F</type><description>
A magical barrier is erected around the dream that prevents visitors
from entering it. It does not prevent visitors from leaving. Anyone
attempting to enter the dream will need to resist this spell or their
attempt will fail.
</description></spell><spell><level>11</level><name>Expell Visitor II</name><areaofeffect>1 visitor</areaofeffect><duration>1 day</duration><range>50'</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Expell Visitor I, except that the target, if he does not resist,
may not reenter the dream for a period of one day. Should the dreamer
start dreaming another dream, however, the visitor may enter that
dream whether a day has passed or not. Note that "Prolonged
Protection" will not affect this. This effect will register as a curse
on the target and may be dispelled as such.
</description><annotation>
For most dreams, one day is much longer than the dream is ever going
to last.
</annotation></spell><spell><level>12</level><name>Prolonged Protection</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>8 hours</duration><range>touch</range><type>U</type><description>
This spell can be used to enhance other spells from this list. Any
spell on this list that would normally end when a dream ends will have
its duration extended to the duration of this spell. In order to
achieve this effect, this spell must be cast prior to and within one
minute of the spell to be affected.
</description><annotation>
This spell will not affect other factors that might cause a spell to
end. As an example, if a "Waiting Wall" spell terminates due to it
being triggered, then this spell will not cause it to live on. The
"Waiting Wall" spell will, however, last a full 8 hours if nothing
should happen to trigger it until then.
</annotation></spell><spell><level>13</level><name>Dream Sentry IV</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>10'</range><type>F</type><description>
As Dream Sentry I, except max creature level is 9 (a class IV entity).
</description></spell><spell><level>14</level><name>Dream Barrier II</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>touch</range><type>F</type><description>
As "Dream Barrier I", except anyone failing will also receive a A
shock critical. The main purpose of this is to cause them to end up in
a dream with a strong "pain" concept, which can be pretty nasty.
Visitors for which pain does not exist (undead or entities without
physical bodies perhaps) are immune to this effect.
</description></spell><spell><level>15</level><name>Dream Perimeter</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>F</type><description>
This spell sets up a perimeter around a dream through which any
visitor that wishes to enter or leave must pass. As they do so, they
must resist this spell or be immobilized for 1 minute
per 10% failure. While they are immobilized, they will not be able to
hide or otherwise meld into the dream and so they will be easier to
find. This spell lasts until the end of the dream in which it was
cast.
</description><annotation>
This spell works well in combination with roaming Dream Sentries.
</annotation></spell><spell><level>16</level><name>Expell Visitor III</name><areaofeffect>1 visitor</areaofeffect><duration>1 day</duration><range>50'</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As "Expell Visitor II", except the target may not return to any dream
of the dreamer for the duration.  It is still possible to
dispell this
effect as a curse.
</description></spell><spell><level>17</level><name/><areaofeffect/></spell><spell><level>18</level><name>Dream Sentry V</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>10'</range><type>F</type><description>
As Dream Sentry I, except max creature level is 13 (a class V entity).
</description></spell><spell><level>19</level><name/><areaofeffect/></spell><spell><level>20</level><name>Dream Fortress</name><areaofeffect>1 spell</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>U</type><description>
When cast before a "Dream Barrier" spell, the target spell will last
until the end of the dream it was cast in. The target spell must be
cast within one minute of this spell.
</description></spell><spell><level>25</level><name>Expell Visitor True</name><areaofeffect>1 visitor</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>50'</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As "Expell Visitor III", except for duration. It is still possible to
dispell this
effect as a curse.
</description></spell><spell><level>30</level><name>Dream Garrison</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>F</type><description>
As "Dream Sentry I", except a number of sentries can be created at
once. The
total entity class of all sentries combined may not exceed the level
of the caster and any one sentry may not be above entity class V (13th
level). The sentries created from one casting of this spell will
function together much like a military unit and will not stray far
from one another.
</description></spell><spell><level>50</level><name>Dream Perimeter True</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>F</type><description>
As "Dream Perimeter", except the effect suffered is not
immobilization. Rather, the caster may choose a spell he is capable of
casting that will affect any non-resisting targets. The caster must
expend the PPs for this spell as he chooses to use it, but does not
need to actually cast it (that is handled by this spell). The target
needs to resist the spell chosen for him, not the "Dream Perimeter
True" spell. The caster may either designate one single spell that
will be used on all intruders, or he may elect to choose a different
spell per occurrence. The caster will be aware when a visitor passes
through the barrier, but will not know who it is or where he is
located.
</description></spell><notes><note>
In order to cast most of the spells on this list, the caster must
"touch" the target, which is "1 dream". To "touch a dream", the caster
must either be inside of that dream (by way of some dream travelling
magic, such as the spell "Enter Dreams I"), or he must touch the actual
dreamer that is having the dream in question.
</note></notes></spelllist>