<?xml version="1.0"?>

<list name="Dream Reality" realm="Channeling" type="Cleric Base">

<description>
This list focuses on taking items and creatures from a dream and using
the power behind them to recreate them in the real world. One ends up
with a highly flexible source of stuff, at the price of stuff that can
behave strangely and that isn't altogether sturdy.
</description>

<spell level="1" name="Enter Dreams I">
<area>self</area>
<duration>C</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>Um</type>
<description>
This spell is normally used to track down the dream from which the
spell caster extracts the objects created by other spells on this
list. The spell gives the caster a mental link into the dream world
through which he can navigate dreams. The link does not yield much in
the way of details, and precise identification of objects within the
dream world is impossible. Only general ideas are transmitted. The
skill "Area Knowledge: Dream World" is used to navigate the dream
world, but a penalty of -20 is applied due to the low quality of the
link. Note that the maintaining of concentration on this spell may
cause additional negative modifiers to be applied to the navigation
skill roll, as well as other activities undertaken within dreams.
</description>
<annotation>
The serious dreamlord will employ spells on the Dream Traveller spell
list for less restricted access to the Dream World.
</annotation>
</spell>

<spell level="2" name="Dream Form I">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
Once the caster has located a dream containing the item he requires,
he may cast this spell to create a replica of that item in the real
world. The item will form on his person or very near him, at his
discretion. The item created by this spell will only roughly resemble
the desired item. No fine detail (such as a keen edge) is possible
and items relying on 
moving parts (like a crossbow) will generally not be functional. The
item will have the texture and general nature of the desired item
though. A rope or a club, for instance, would be quite functional. The
item may
not weigh more than 0.5 lbs.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="3" name="Dream Item I">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Form I, except fine detail is possible. Thus, functional
knives and
crossbows are quite feasible. Note, however, that the functionality
depends on the dreamer's familiarity with the design of the type of
item in question. As an example, a skeleton key procured from a master
locksmith's dream might be a wonderful tool but a skeleton key
obtained from a foot soldier's dream might be rather useless even if
it does <em>look</em> pretty fancy (the foot soldier's key is still
perfectly functional <em>within his dream</em> though, but that's
a different matter).
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="4" name="Dream Creature II">
<area>1 creature</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Form I, except a creature can be created. The creature will
never be intelligent, and will generally behave in the manner in which
the
original dreamer thinks consistent with its nature. The creature
cannot communicate meaningfully and it is not under the control of the
caster. It is considered an "entity" from the dream world for the
purposes of control,
banishing, etc. If the creature attacks, it will have the OBs of a
Created Undead of its level. This spell can create creatures that
weigh no more than 1 pound per level of the caster and that are no
more than level 3 (a class II entity).
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="5" name="Improve Integrity I">
<area>1 target</area>
<duration>P</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
When cast upon a dream object or creature created by other spells on
this list, the integrity of that object or creature is improved by 10%.
Normally, this will result in a 40% chance of the target dissipating
after a violent blow as opposed to the normal 50%. Multiple castings
of this type of spell upon the same item do <em>not</em> yield
cumulative 
bonuses.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="6" name="Dream Form II">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Form I, except weight limit is 5 pounds.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="7" name="Prolong Dream I">
<area>1 dream</area>
<duration>1 min/level</duration>
<range>-</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
When cast upon a dream, will ensure that any items or creatures
obtained from that dream will have a duration of at least 1 minute per
level of the caster. After this duration ends, normal chance of the
item or creature disappearing will resume.
 Note that if the caster
maintains this spell for an extended period of time (which is only
really an issue for the higher level versions), the effect on the
dreamer is that he will not wake up. From the outside, this will
appear like a disease or a curse and any attempts to cure the malady
as one of these have a chance of being successful. The Prolong Dream
spell will use its own level to resist any such attempts.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="8" name="Magical Dreams">
<area>special</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
When cast before any of the "Dream ...." spells on this list, will
allow the created item or creature to have innate magical abilities.
Such enchantments must be of a nature that directly affects only the
created item. They can only indirectly affect other items or beings,
and they cannot project more than a few inches from the item itself.
A flying carpet, a self-tying rope or a glowing cat is ok but a wand
of firebolts, a 
spell adder or a fire-breathing lizard is not. The magical effect can
not be of a higher level 
than one fifth that of the caster.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="9" name="Dream Item II">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Item I except weight limit is 5 lbs.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="10" name="Improve Integrity II">
<area>1 target</area>
<duration>P</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Improve Integrity I, except integrity improvement is 20%.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="11" name="Dream Creature III">
<area>1 creature</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Creature II, except max weight is 5 lbs pr level of the
caster, and max creature level is 6 (a class III enitity).
</description>
</spell>


<spell level="12" name="Dream Form III">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Form I, except max weight is 20 lbs.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="13" name="Prolong Dream II">
<area>1 dream</area>
<duration>5 min/level</duration>
<range>-</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Prolong Dream I except for duration.
</description>
</spell>


<spell level="14" name="Dream Item III">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Item, except max weight is 20 lbs.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="15" name="Improve Integrity III">
<area>1 target</area>
<duration>P</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Improve Integrity, except integrity bonus is 30%.
</description>
</spell>



<spell level="16" name="Dream Creature IV">
<area>1 creature</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Creature II, except max weight is 10 lbs pr level of the
caster and max creature level is 9 (a class IV entity).
</description>
</spell>


<spell level="17" name="Dream Form X">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Form I except max weight is 100 lbs.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="18" name="Prolong Dream III">
<area>1 dream</area>
<duration>30 min/level</duration>
<range>-</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Prolong Dream I except for duration.
</description>
</spell>


<spell level="19" name="Dream Item X">
<area>1 item</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Item I, except max weight is 100 lbs.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="20" name="Dream Creature V">
<area>1 creature</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Creature II, except max weight is 100 lbs pr level of the
caster and max creature level is 13 (a class V entity).
</description>
</spell>


<spell level="25" name="Improve Integrity True">
<area>1 target</area>
<duration>P</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Improve Integrity I, except decreases fragility to 0%, therefore
giving no chance of the item breaking when struck. It should still
check for normal breakage when called for, however.
</description>
</spell>

<spell level="30" name="Prolong Dream True">
<area>1 dream</area>
<duration>C</duration>
<range>-</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Prolong Dream I, except for the duration.
</description>
</spell>


<spell level="50" name="Dream World">
<area>2'R/level</area>
<duration>special</duration>
<range>self</range>
<type>F</type>
<description>
As Dream Item X and Dream Creature V, except an entire scene can be
created and will replace the real scenery at the target location for
the duration. Any number of items and creatures needed to populate the
scene will be created. In addition, for each magical effect desired
in the scene, the spell Magical Dreams can be cast once before the
casting of this spell.
</description>
</spell>


<specialnote>
Before anything can be created by the spells on this list, a dream
must successfully have been located that contains the item(s) desired.
This requires a means of navigating the dream world and the skill to
do so successfully. The former is provided as the first level spell
"Enter Dreams I", although enterprising spell casters may find better
ways of accomplishing the same. The latter requires a successful "Area
Knowledge: Dream World" once the former has been taken care of. The
difficulty of this skill roll should be determined by the GM based
upon how specific or obscure the requested item is. The more specific and
the more obscure, the more difficult. If it's something noone ever
dreams about, it's simply impossible. This shouldn't happen a lot
though, there's lots of totally weird stuff in people's dreams.
</specialnote>

<specialnote>
The duration of a created item is special. The item is formed from the
dreams of some individual, and dreams are fickle things. One moment
it's there, the next moment it's gone. If the identity or nature of
the individual having the dream from which the item is collected is
not known or not of interest, the following duration should be used.
For every five minutes, there is a 50% chance that the dream shifts in
such a way that the item no longer exists within it in its original
form and the item disappears. The exact moment within the five minute
period at which the item disappears should be determined randomly.
This means that there is a risk the item will disappear immediately,
and one shouldn't expect it to last more than 5-7 minutes on the
average. Note that the "Prolong Dream" spells on this list give some
guaranteed duration.
</specialnote>

<specialnote>
Stuff created from dreams can be as fickle as the dreams themselves.
They only have a weak link to the real world and, in addition, they are
subject to the whims of the dreamer. The result is that they are
rather fragile. The fragility of a dream item is 50% by default. Each
time a dream item or creature receives a violent blow, this is the
chance that it 
will disappear. Note that the "Improve Integrity" spells on this list
can affect the fragility of an item or creature.
</specialnote>

<specialnote>
Items or creatures created from dreams are still under the power of
the dream they originated from. The most interesting effect of this is
that they will perform consistently with how they would have performed
within the dream, not with how similar items perform in the real
world. This means that if the caster chooses the "wrong" dream, the
knife he created might prove to be an excellent flute, but useless at
puncturing things, etc. This would depend to a large extent on the
strength of the "reality" concept in the source dream, and casters are
well advised to seek out dreams that are strong in "reality" if they
desire items that perform predictably.
</specialnote>

</list>
