<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<spelllist><name>Dream Traveller</name><listtype>Channeling Cleric Base </listtype><author>Bent Dalager</author><description>
This list facilitates travel through the dream world. It lets the
spell caster move his mind into the realm of dreams and it makes it
easier for him to move around once there.
</description><spell><level>1</level><name>Enter Dreams I</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
This spell gives the caster a weak mental link into
the
dream world
through which he can navigate dreams. The link does not yield much in
the way of details, and precise identification of objects within the
dream world is impossible. Only general ideas are transmitted. The
skill "Area Knowledge: Dream World" is used to navigate the dream
world, but a penalty of -20 is applied due to the low quality of the
link. Note that the maintaining of concentration on this spell may
cause additional negative modifiers to be applied to the navigation
skill roll, as well as other activities undertaken within dreams.
</description></spell><spell><level>2</level><name>Remember Dream</name><areaofeffect>1 dream</areaofeffect><duration>P</duration><range>touch</range><type>Um</type><description>
The caster memorizes the nature and contents of one dream in order to
use other spells on this list on that dream later. Even if the dream
has ended, this spell can be useful should that dream come again. It
is therefore mostly useful for long dreams or recurring dreams. The
caster can memorize any number of dreams by the use of this spell.
</description></spell><spell><level>3</level><name>Visit Dreams I</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>1 min/level</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Enter Dreams I except for duration.
</description></spell><spell><level>4</level><name>Seek Dream I</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
Can only be cast on dreams that are remembered as per the spell
"Remember Dream". The spell will mold the caster's mind so that one
single concept from the target dream will be present in his mind at
the appropriate size. This
will effectively bring the caster "closer" to that dream.
</description></spell><spell><level>5</level><name>Travel Link I</name><areaofeffect>1 target</areaofeffect><duration>special</duration><range>touch</range><type>Um</type><description>
Caster links his mind to the target (who must be awake at the time of
casting), allowing the target to travel
into the dream world together with the caster, and molding the state
of his own mind in synchronization with the caster. In effect, the
target becomes a hitchhiker on the caster's journey into the dream
world. While the target will have freedom of action and movement
within the environment of any one dream, his state of mind is
inextricably linked to that of the caster, and so his travel between
different dreams is also linked to that of the caster. Any successful
attempt by
the target to change his own state of mind will break the spell and
thrust him back into the waking world. The duration of the spell
is so long as the caster remains within the dream world, or 2 minutes
if the caster has not yet entered it. This means that the caster can
cast this spell upon a target and wait up to two minutes before
entering the dream world. The caster can cast this spell on multiple
targets and take them all with him.
</description></spell><spell><level>6</level><name>Mold Mind V</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
Caster introduces, removes, strengthens or weakens one single dream
concept in his own
state of mind. A newly introduced concept must enter at size 1-5. An
already existing one can be strengthened or weakened by 5 sizes. One
that is size 5 or smaller can be removed entirely. This can be used to
bring the caster's state of mind closer to that of his target dream.
</description></spell><spell><level>7</level><name>Enter Dreams II</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Enter Dreams I, except the dream world is experienced with great
clarity and there is no special penalty to interacting with it. There
may still be a penalty for maintaining concentration on this spell
though.
</description></spell><spell><level>8</level><name>Travel Link V</name><areaofeffect>5 targets</areaofeffect><duration>special</duration><range>10'</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Travel Link I, except for area of effect.
</description></spell><spell><level>9</level><name>Visit Dreams II</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>10 min/level</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Enter Dreams II, except for duration.
</description></spell><spell><level>10</level><name>Remain</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>1 min/level</duration><range>self</range><type>Fm</type><description>
Caster roots himself firmly within a dream. Any attempt to dislodge
the caster or visitors "Travel Linked" to him will face a -50
penalty to doing so.
</description></spell><spell><level>11</level><name>Mold Mind X</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Mold Mind V, except any existing concept can be removed regardless
of size, any new concept can be introduced to any size and any
existing concept can be resized to any size.
</description></spell><spell><level>12</level><name>Dream Agent</name><areaofeffect>1 target</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>touch</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Visit Dreams I, except for area of effect.
</description></spell><spell><level>13</level><name>Seek Dream V</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Seek Dream I, except up to five concepts are put in place.
</description></spell><spell><level>14</level><name>Resist Concept</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>special</duration><range>self</range><type>Fm</type><description>
The caster must choose one specific concept that is not currently
present within his frame of mind. Any attempt to introduce that
concept upon the caster will suffer a -50 penalty. The duration lasts
so long as the caster remains within the dream world or until the
concept is successfully forced upon the caster.
</description></spell><spell><level>15</level><name>Travel Link True</name><areaofeffect>1 target/level</areaofeffect><duration>special</duration><range>100'</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Travel Link I, except for area of effect.
</description></spell><spell><level>16</level><name>Filter Dreams</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
Gives the caster mental images of a whole specter of active dreams
that match his current state of mind. This spell effectively negates
the need for the caster to
actually visit a myriad of dreams to find one specific target dream.
He will only need to get to one out of the myraid if similar dreams
and then employ this spell.
Note that the maintaining of concentration of this
spell does not give penalties to any skill checks used to filter out
the dreams.
</description></spell><spell><level>17</level><name>Hide</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>1 round/level</duration><range>self</range><type>F</type><description>
The caster becomes difficult to detect by normal means within the
dream world. Any attempts to detect him will suffer a -70 (Sheer
Folly) penalty.
</description></spell><spell><level>18</level><name>Visit Dreams III</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>1 hour/level</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Visit Dreams II except for duration.
</description></spell><spell><level>19</level><name>Avoid Visitors</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>1 min/level</duration><range>self</range><type>U</type><description>
For the duration of this spell, the caster will be predisposed towards
entering dreams that do not contain overt visitors. Covert visitors
may reduce the probability of being avoided, depending upon the
quality of their covertness. Any dream with visitors in it that would
otherwise have been chosen as the caster's next dream has a base 95%
chance of not being entered and the caster will end up in another
similar dream in stead. The caster does not know when this
has happened.
</description></spell><spell><level>20</level><name>Dream Army</name><areaofeffect>1 target/level</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>100'</range><type>Fm</type><description>
As Dream Agent, except for area of effect and range.
</description></spell><spell><level>25</level><name>Seek Dream True</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Seek Dream I, except all dream concepts are put into place, thereby
putting the caster's state of mind in exact sync with the remembered
dream.
</description></spell><spell><level>30</level><name>Mold Mind True</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>-</duration><range>self</range><type>Um</type><description>
As Mold Mind X, except can affect any number of dream concepts in one go.
</description></spell><spell><level>50</level><name>Preparation</name><areaofeffect>self</areaofeffect><duration>C</duration><range>self</range><type>U</type><description>
While under the influence of this spell, the caster may cast any "Seek
Dream" and "Mold Mind"
spells on this list without first entering
the dream world. He must still cast them normally and pay the power
point costs, etc. Concentration on the maintenance of this spell does
not negatively affect his ability to cast such spells. What this spell
gives the caster is basically a way of achieving the correct mental
state before entering the dream world, thereby potentially avoiding a
lot of grief.
</description></spell><notes><note>
All "Seek Dream" and "Mold Mind" spells on this list require the
caster to already
be within the dream world. The 50th level spell "Preparation" negates
this requirement.
</note></notes></spelllist>