<?xml version='1.0'?>

<!DOCTYPE spelllist SYSTEM
        "/home/nash/work/rolemaster/XML/spelllist/spelllist.dtd">


<spelllist>
    <name>Sand Law</name>
    <listtype>Magician Additional Base</listtype>
    <author>P.H. Bongo (phb-ml@hotpop.com)</author>
    <author>edited by Brett Nash</author>
    <spell>
        <level>1</level>
        <name>Sandwalking</name>
        <areaofeffect>caster</areaofeffect>
        <duration>10 min/lvl</duration>
        <range>self</range>
        <type>U</type>
        <description> 
          The caster can walk on sand as if it were packed earth. He
          leaves no traces.  
        </description>
        <description>
          Second paragraph
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>2</level>
        <name>Erase Tracks</name>
        <areaofeffect>20' Radius</areaofeffect>
        <duration>C</duration>
        <range>self</range>
        <type>U</type>
        <description>
          Erases all tracks, including those made by others, behind the
          caster in a 20' wide swath as long as he concentrates.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>3</level>
        <name>Dig I</name>
        <areaofeffect>20'Rx20'Deep</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration> 
        <range>100'</range> 
        <type>F</type> 
        <description>
          Will make an up to 20' deep pit in sand. The pit is dug conically
          so that the sides do not collapse, even without magic. Normally,
          wind and shifting earth will cause the pit to be filled in in a
          matter of days.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>4</level>
        <name>Churning Dust</name>
        <areaofeffect>10'x10'x5'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>1 round/lvl</duration>
        <range>50'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          Causes a 10' by 10' by 5' wall of churning sand and dust to rise.
          Gives 80 to missile attacks, -40 to melee attacks and visibility
          is limited (-50 to visual skills/checks).
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>5</level>
        <name>Sand Dune I</name>
        <areaofeffect>50'x20'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>50'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          Will throw up a sand dune, 10' high in the middle, 10'-20' wide
          and 30' to 50' long, sloping away at the ends. The dune has
          equally sloping sides, although an Easy Spell Mastery can make one
          side steeper than the other.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>6</level>
        <name>Shelter</name>
        <areaofeffect>5'x10'x5'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>12 hours</duration>
        <range>touch</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          Will make an foxhole in sand, 5' by 10', 5' high and a 3' opening.
          It will hold during sandstorms. The walls are insulating, so the
          experienced desert-traveller will make it early in the morning so
          it keeps cool during the day, or early in the evening, so it stays
          warm during night,
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>7</level>
        <name>Dig II</name>
        <areaofeffect>20'Rx40'Pit</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>150'</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          As <ref>Dig I</ref>, but the pit will be 40' deep.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>8</level>
        <name>Sand Tower</name>
        <areaofeffect>30'x5'R</areaofeffect>
        <duration>1 round/lvl (C.)</duration>
        <range>self</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          The spell forms a cylinder of sand, 30' tall and 5' wide. If the
          caster casts it under his feet, it will carry him up with it. It
          will hold for the duration without concentration, but if it is
          attacked or in other ways being actively weakened, concentration
          will be needed to keep it from collapsing.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>9</level>
        <name>Breathe Sand</name>
        <areaofeffect>1 person</areaofeffect>
        <duration>1 hour/lvl</duration>
        <range>touch</range>
        <type>U</type>
        <description>
          Allows target to breathe under sand as if in air. The target must
          have a mouth cover,  to stop mouth filling with sand.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>10</level>
        <name>Sand Carries</name>
        <areaofeffect>20'R</areaofeffect>
        <duration>10 min/lvl(special)</duration>
        <range>self</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          This will  make the surface of the sand around the caster in a 20'
          radius harden enough to carry a pack animal with a rider. As the
          caster moves, new areas will be subjected to the spell for the
          duration (10 min/lvl). This hardness will last for 1 round/level.
          All tracks will be erased when the effect wears off.
        </description> 
    </spell>
    <spell> 
        <level>11</level> 
        <name>Dig III</name> 
        <areaofeffect>30'Rx60'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration> 
        <range>200'</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description> 
          As <ref>Dig I</ref>, except pit will be 60' deep.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>12</level>
        <name>Sand Blast</name>
        <duration>-</duration> 
        <range>100'</range> 
        <type>BE</type> 
        <description>
          Gathers up sand and hurls it at a target; attack is resolved on
          Water Ball attack table.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>13</level>
        <name>Quicksand</name>
        <areaofeffect>1000 cu'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>1 min/lvl</duration>
        <range>100'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          This will make a 10' by 10' patch of sand into quicksand. It will
          be roughly 10' deep, if the sand goes that deep. The time needed
          to form the quicksand varies from 3 rounds to 20 minutes,
          depending on the amount of water nearby and the air moisture.
          Spells from Water Law or similar lists can cut the time
          considerably, though not under 3 rounds. (If the full time
          required is not spent, the fraction of time taken is proportional
          to the depth of the quicksand.) The water will evaporate according
          to local conditions.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>14</level>
        <name>Sand Dune II</name>
        <areaofeffect>100'x40'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>100'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          As <ref>Sand Dune I</ref>, except dune is 20' high, 20'-40' wide
          and 50' to 100' long.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>15</level>
        <name>Burrow</name>
        <areaofeffect>caster</areaofeffect>
        <duration>1 round/lvl</duration>
        <range>self</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          Allows caster to dig through sand at a rate of 5'/round. The
          tunnel will be 5' wide. It will hold for the duration of the
          spell.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>16</level>
        <name>Earth to Sand</name>
        <areaofeffect>10K cu'</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>touch</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          This spell will turn 10,000 cubic feet of earth to sand. The spell
          will draw the water out of the earth; the caster must give a
          location for the water to be deposited, otherwise it will pool on
          top of the sand.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>17</level>
        <name>Sanding</name>
        <areaofeffect>1 target</areaofeffect>
        <duration></duration>
        <range>100'</range>
        <type>DE</type>
        <description>
          The caster directs a stream of sand onto the target. The stream
          can cover a circle with a radius of 2'. If used offensively, the
          attack is resolved on the Fire Bolt table, with Unbalancing
          criticals instead of Heat. The damage given is divided between the
          target himself and the armor he's wearing.  Every round the stream
          is centered on the target counts as a new attack.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>18</level>
        <name>Bury</name>
        <areaofeffect>1 target</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>200'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          This spell will  bury the target at a rate of 100 cubic feet per
          round. The target must fit inside a circle with a radius of 50'.
          The caster must concentrate each round; otherwise the target will
          stop sinking. The spell can sink the target 40' below ground
          level, but only if there is sand down that far. Is the target
          cannot sink anymore, further concentration will heap sand onto the
          target until a 40' tall sand hill has built up.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>19</level>
        <name>Sand Castle</name>
        <areaofeffect>see below</areaofeffect>
        <duration>24 hours</duration>
        <range>50'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          This spell allows the caster to make a number of sandwalls. The
          caster can make sandwalls of 15' height, 2' thick and up to 200'
          long in any shape; OR, the caster can cast the spell on up to four
          sand dunes created by Sand Dune spells, in which case the dunes
          are shaped into walls that are double the height of the dune, same
          length and 5' thick.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>20</level>
        <name>Sand Storm</name>
        <areaofeffect>100'R</areaofeffect>
        <duration>1 min/lvl</duration>
        <range>500'</range>
        <type>E</type>
        <description>
          A sand storm is created in the area of effect. At it's most
          effective, when cast in a desert, visibility is 2', speed is
          reduced to a tenth, all missile attacks suffer a 100 penalty, all
          melee Attacks a 50 penalty and everyone in the area must make a RR
          vs 1st level or suffer an A Heat Critical. In other terrains, the
          effectiveness of the spell lessens: Half effect in plains, quarter
          effect in grasslands, hills or mountains, no effect in swamps or
          at sea. A Sheer Folly Spell Mastery might make the spell work in a
          snowfield, creating a Snow Storm with the same effects, except
          Cold instead of Heat Criticals.  Finally, if spell is cast in a
          natural sandstorm, the effect is at least doubled, the details are
          left to the GMs imagination. 
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>25</level>
        <name>Harden</name> 
        <areaofeffect>1000'cu or special</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>touch</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          A mass of sand is compressed into sandstone. This is done by
          drawing more sand in, so the volume remains the same. The volume
          of effect is 1000 cubic feet unless it is cast on something
          created by a lower level spell on this list within a minute after
          the target has reached the desired form, in which case it works on
          the entire structure. For Shelter, Burrow and the Dig spells, this
          spells compresses the surrounding sand  to a depth of one foot.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell> 
        <level>30</level>
        <name>Stone to Sand</name> 
        <areaofeffect>1K/10K cu'</areaofeffect> 
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>touch</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          Turns 1000 cubic feet of stone to sand unless cast on sandstone in
          which case 10,000 cubic feet crumbles becomes sand again.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <level>50</level>
        <name>Spread Desert</name>
        <areaofeffect>1 mile R</areaofeffect>
        <duration>P</duration>
        <range>self</range>
        <type>F</type>
        <description>
          Sets the area of effect (1 mile radius around caster) on the way
          to become a desert. Water evaporates, streams are led underground,
          grass dies, roots wither, etc. Larger growths and trees might get
          a RR on the GMs discretion.  If the area is tended by an animist,
          druid, nature deity or something similar, the entire area gets a
          RR, using the level of the animist etc. If it is tended by a
          skilled gardenerer without magical skills, the area gets a RR
          using level. This spell does not keep the area dry after the spell
          is cast. If it rains frequently and heavily, the area will become
          a large mud hole.
        </description>
    </spell>
    <notes>
        <note>
          All spells require that there is enough sand, dust or loose earth
          present to perform the effects (except Earth to Sand, Stone to
          Sand and Spread Desert)
        </note>
    </notes>
</spelllist>

