<?xml version='1.0'?>

<spelllist>
        <name>Dreamscape</name>
        <type>Reann Cleric Special list</type>
        <author>Wade Aaron</author>
        <description>
	There is a special list that sometimes Clerics of Reann
receive.  It is called Dreamscape:
        </description>

	<spell>
                <level>1</level>
                <name>Nightmare</name>
                <range>1 sleep period</range>
                <duration>25' +5'/lvl</duration>
                Target has one night of
very bad dreams.  If the being wakes up, the nightmares will resume if
sleep is resumed.

	</spell><spell><level>2</level><name>Daydream</name><range>up to 1 hour</range><duration>S</duration>Caster has short daydream on a topic
decided upon just before fading out.  Liminted to 1x/day.

	</spell><spell><level>3</level><name>Dream Other</name><range>1 sleep period</range><duration>T</duration>Willing target will have a dream
on a topic decided upon by the caster.  Limited to 1x/night.

	</spell><spell><level>4</level><name>Sleep Detection</name><range>1 min/lvl</range><duration>100'</duration>R Caster knows if there is
sentient sleeping beings within the range of this spell and their
general direction.

	</spell><spell><level>5</level><name>Find Dreamer</name><range>C</range><duration>100'</duration>R Caster knows the direction of a
particular person who is sleeping and their general state of being.
Caster must either know the person or have an article of the person
(bedding item, nightgown, hair, etc.)

	</spell><spell><level>6</level><name>Recall Dream</name><range>V</range><duration>T</duration>A dream can be recalled in exact detail and
clear of post-dream embellishment.  Dreams up to 1 month per level can
be recalled.

	</spell><spell><level>7</level><name>Sleepwalk</name><range>1 min/lvl</range><duration>100'</duration>Target will rise and walk in their
sleep to a general area or direction as determined by the caster.
Target can do simple functions (opening and/or unbarring a door) to
achieve goal.  If target is target is shaken strongly or caused pain,
the spell is broken.

	</spell><spell><level>8</level><name>Sleeptalking</name><range>1 min/lvl</range><duration>10'</duration>Caster can speak to target and
target will respond aloud seeing the questioner (caster) as any person
the caster so desires.  If the caster changes direction of
questioning, the targets dreams change to match.

	</spell><spell><level>9</level><name>Share Dream</name><range>1 hour/lvl</range><duration>10'</duration>+ 2'/lvl Caster enters targets
dreams and can be either an unseen observer or active participant.

	</spell><spell><level>10</level><name>Protect Sleeper</name><range>1 sleep period</range><duration>T</duration>Recipient of this spell is
protected from magical spells that would harm the sleeper.  Creatures
that would attack the sleeper's psyche or spirit are also repelled.
This spell can be cast while sleeping, if the priest is under attack
that would be warded by this spell.  The sleeper does not necessarily
know that an attack was made.

	</spell><spell><level>12</level><name>Dream Interpretation</name><range>-</range><duration>S</duration>Caster knows the meaning and origin
or cause of any dream told to or dreamed by him by the caster.  Caster
also knows if portions missing or have been embellished.  Used upon
oneself, immediately upon awaking it has the added benefit of giving a
timeframe for prophetic dreams.

	</spell><spell><level>14</level><name>Night Terror</name><range>special</range><duration>25'</duration>+5'/lvl Target is marked by an
invisible symbol that draws the angry attention of a 'Carrier of
Dreams'.  The next time the target is asleep, unconcious, or in a
dream-like state, they receive that is so real it cannot be
distinguished in life.  In this dream, that which they fear the most
comes forth.  Often, the dream begins with the target dreaming they
have awakened.  Failure to truly awaken (RR fail miss by 50 or more)
means they die.  Failure less than 50, the target acts as if under a confusion
spell, for 1 minute per 5 failure.  Anything that decreases the chance
of the target awakening increases the likelihood of the target dying.
DM note: People who live through such traumatic experiences may
receive XP, DM's call.

	</spell><spell><level>15</level><name>Dream Talk</name><range>1 min/lvl</range><duration>S</duration>Caster 'wakes up' in the target's
dream and can speak to the person.  Of course target must be asleep
when the spell is cast, or all is for naught.  Base 50% chance that
the spell will succeed, modified by the following factors:
Previous Dream Talk, or shared dream:  +50
Previous Dream Interpretation or Other:  +40
Caster knows person well:  +40
Caster knows person casually:  +20
Caster has met person once:  +0
Caster has seen person:  -20
Person has been described to caster:  -40
Caster's lvl = +1 bonus/lvl

	</spell><spell><level>17</level><name>Sleeplessness</name><range>1 day/lvl</range><duration>S</duration>Caster can go without sleep with
no detrimental effects for as many days as he has levels.

	</spell><spell><level>18</level><name>Dream Share True</name><range>1 hour/lvl</range><duration>S</duration>As Dream Share, except caster
can share dreams with someone who is unwilling.  Note this can be cast
in conjunction with Dream Walk.

	</spell><spell><level>20</level><name>Dream Walk</name><range>10 min/lvl</range><duration>S</duration>Caster's dream body arises from
sleeping body, and he may project himself anywhere it is night.
Caster is immaterial, and has no effect on objects.  He can be seen
only be people who are alseep, and the Carriers.

	</spell><spell><level>25</level><name>Dreamless</name><range>P</range><duration>100'</duration>+10'/lvl Target ceases to dream.  Insanity
follows.  Target can attone for wrongdoing.

	</spell><spell><level>30</level><name>Dream with Dead</name><range>V</range><duration>S</duration>Caster lays down among the dead, in
their crypt, or the clothes they died in.  He then dreams the dreams
they have just prior to death.  Target must have died withing 1
month/lvl of caster.  It is possible to dream with the long deceased
by a ritual that is comprised in part of this spell.

	</spell><spell><level>50</level><name>Dream Cast</name><range>1 sleep period</range><duration>S</duration>Caster can cast any spell on his
Dreams list that he so desires, limited to 1 spell/lvl of caster.
        </spell>
</spelllist>
